a mouthful bro um thank you for for the
background and the education man I a lot
of this stuff is even new to me um one
okay a lot of what you just said sounds
a lot like uh the Jehovah's witness's
faith that I'm pretty familiar with
right they also believe that Jesus is um
Michael reincarnated as Michael the
Archangel um and when I had
conversations with them they clearly
believe that Jesus is not the Eternal
God right that he is a created being
Michael the Archangel right but when we
put this online and it was all in the
comments there were multiple people who
believe or said they believe that who
were SDA they they said they believe
that Jesus was the Eternal God and that
he was not that that that he was
referred to as Michael the Archangel but
at the same time like that was just one
of his names but he is the Eternal God
the same thing that um Orthodox
Christians believe and so can you
explain like is is it is it them just
clearly having a misunderstanding of the
historical background of the of the Sea
church that you just gave um like why do
you think well to me it seems like so
many Christians don't mean so many sdas
don't believe that or don't understand
the church history in that way yeah does
that make sense yeah a lot of what what
the Adventist Church does is
that because for them subconsciously
Ellen White is
infallible there are those back in the
day used to be straight up and say she's
infallible but these days especially
since the
1950s with the Evangelical dialogues
with Dr Walter Martin they're more shy
to just Embrace what they actually
believe and so they cover up a lot of
these
teachings with proof text from scripture
and verbiage of auth oxy and so they
believe that exact theology about
Michael the Archangel in fact the
Jehovah's Witnesses when they came
around in
1879 they got that theology from sth Day
Adventist wow I didn't know that
Witnesses
founder influenced by seventh day
adventism so Soul sleep and Michael the
Archangel and a number of other things
jobah Witnesses got from Seventh Day
Adventist and they to be uh faithful to
the original teaching but because
adventism now start to get a lot of
flack and they want to appear to be more
Orthodox just like everybody else they
have piled on a lot
of verbiage and proof text of Orthodoxy
to make it look like we are Orthodox and
we've always been that way and so that
is why you see they'll they'll run
through scripture to prove that the
angel of the Lord in the Old Testament
is Michael the Archangel and all of
these different things that Michael is
the only Arch Angel and it simply means
chief of the angels and the list goes on
yeah so what they've done they still
have the original teaching but they pile
on a lot of things that make it look
Orthodox so so and there are some SD who
don't seem to know that so let me so let
me ask you this I know one of the
reasons well one of the ways in which
the Jehovah's Witnesses tried to just
IFI that Jesus is Michael the Archangel
because in 1950 they published The New
World Translation right um that changed
the original Greek text like John 1 it
says in the beginning was the word and
the Word was with God and the Word was a
God not the god um he was in the
beginning with God through him all other
things were created right and so they
they changed the the person of Christ
there they also miss highly I know
misinterpret the scriptures where it
says that you know that g in
Thessalonians I think it says that Jesus
Will descend with the voice of an
archangel and the sound of a trumpet
doesn't say he is an archangel he say he
have the voice of an archangel right and
so I these are passages that I talk to
Jehovah's Witnesses about but the seven
day event is they they don't have
another translation of the Bible or I
wouldn't even call it I wouldn't call
the New World Translation respectfully a
translation I think it's another I think
it's a perverted version of the Bible
but the SDA people they you know SDA
Church they had they read the Bible and
so how do they justify Jesus not being
the Eternal God but a created being
Michael the Archangel how do they what
how did they come to that to that
understanding although most
Advent okay we're gonna keep it going
yeah Adventists do have a version of the
Bible they've created whoa okay the
clear word bible you could look it up
online wow the Clare word bible I'm
going to look it up now written and
published by a 7th Adventist Professor
it is published by an official organ of
the 7th Adventist Church the review and
Herald publishing association
association and it is also used in the
Seventh Day Adventist Church although
not widely it is sold in Adventist
bookstores all over the world as a Bible
under the section of Bibles wow and when
you read the CLA word version the Clare
word bible of Adventist they do the very
same things that Jehovah's Witnesses do
in their Bible and
so scripture is is is butchered
reinterpreted distorted to agree with
Seventh Day Adventist doctrines and
teachings in their clear word bible are
you saying that they that they minimize
Jesus for being the Eternal God and
makes him and make him a God because I
think people will hear you say that and
me like what do you mean we do the same
thing as Jehovah's Witnesses because in
the Bible when it refers to Jesus being
God Almighty it clearly say says that he
is not God Almighty right and when you
talk to Jehovah's Witness they would
Clearly say no we don't believe that
Jesus is God Almighty we believe that he
is Michael the AR Angel the Son of God
that God was the first person that the
first being that God created as a master
worker to to create the heavens and the
Earth and all the all of the things and
so when you said that it does the same
thing in which way does it does the same
thing I just want to for clarity sake
for example if you read in the clar
Bible of of Jude
9 Michael the Ain
is referring to
Jesus um Ellen White has a lot of
statements in which she say for
example okay
y'all I've never seen such a deep magic
trick like what I just watched just now
and and what I appreciate have you ever
read the clear word bible we're getting
there Derek um I've never read the clear
word bible I have to say that okay Derek
from Jamaica what's up man and I know I
said 15 uh 15 fact checks and what we're
on fact check six five I know I know
it's going to be a marathon but I'm
gonna try to get through this it's just
that I think if people see one fact
check and go well if the scholarship was
like this on that fact check what else
did he get wrong and I'm going through
we're on fact check number five and six
right now and I just kind of lumped a
bunch all together but I want y'all to
follow this okay because Preston was
like hold on I deal with Jehovah's
Witnesses I know what they say and
Adventists are saying something
different and and Elsie and I don't know
if it was a moment of
conviction where I feel like I saw
something in his face where he knew I'm
not telling the truth right now and man
this is I'm on a hot seat right and I
better make something up and and I want
y'all to follow cuz I I track this for
you okay so let's go back to the screen
fact check
sdas believe like Jehovah's Witnesses
regarding Jesus as a created being so
remember now we haven't fact check
number 3 four five or six yet which is
the clear word demotes Jesus so now
watch the conversation watch this Elsie
said earlier SD believe that Jesus was
promoted to D status as if he okay like
he wasn't already there still Elsie then
turns around and says sda's deny the
deity
Jesus y'all put a one in the chat if you
if you caught what I just did y'all saw
what just
happened Elsie said earlier that
Adventist believe that Jesus was exalted
by God to deity status but then he comes
right back and says sdas don't
believe that Jesus right is
God come on y'all so now watch this
watch the Preston says this Advent is
pushed back they say they believe that
Jesus is the Eternal God but Michael is
just one of his names so Preston is
saying listen are they saying that okay
yeah we know that Jesus they say that
Jesus is Michael but they're saying
unlike Jehovah's Witnesses that they
believe that Jesus is not a created
being so that's Preston's first thing
Elsie responds watch this he doesn't
answer he goes into Ellen White
infallible Walter Martin uh they cover
the teaching with proof text they
believe the exact theology about Michael
Jehovah's Witnesses they pile on a lot
of verbiage and the original teaching
and I'm watching this y'all and I'm
like I'm not judging the heart but I
almost feel like and let me be quiet so
Preston comes back he pushes back and
he's like but how do SAS justify Jesus
as a created being they don't have their
own Bible and then Elsie jumps onto that
they do have their own Bible and they do
the same thing and it's the clear word
Bible and then Preston pushes back again
go Preston he was sincere he was he's
sincere he's like yeah I I hear you but
I know about JW's and I'm getting pushed
back from Adventist and to me I felt
like he was like now we're not going to
misrepresent administ on here but then
LC came back was like no that's what
Adventist believe and because Preston
doesn't know much about adventism he's
like oh okay well man that's what what
they believe that's really
problematic nether does pastor Mason
like he was like they do have another
they do have another Bible I'm going to
Google that right now well wouldn't you
have known that if we really had that
had you done your own research and wrote
your own chapter but in asking write a
book about about a whole denomination
being a cult and you ask someone else to
write the book to write the chapter I'm
I'm sorry MH that means you can't do it
that you don't have enough information
so Preston pushes back he's like yeah
but does the bible demote Jesus to the
status of a created being in the same in
which uh the the Jehovah's Witness do
the same thing does the does the clear
word do what the New World Translation
does and Elsie responds like this if you
look at Jude nine it refers to Michael
as
Jesus whoa we already know that we
already know that advent is believe that
by Preston ask you a straightup question
does the clear word demote Jesus and
Elsie's response was Jude nine they say
that Jesus is Michael that's what
Preston started
with okay let's go back to the screen so
now here's what's going on here's what
goes out before thousands of people
watch this look at the
screen this is on the Perry's YouTube
page adventism reject
the deity of
Christ now why does Preston have that up
there because he was told
this by Elsie yeah thousands of people
are looking at this and receiving a
false message so watch watch this y'all
here's what Elsie didn't do when Preston
brought up when Preston brought up well
what about John 1 in the New World
Translation Elsie should have said well
let's see what John 1:1 says in the
clear word right here's the clear word
you guys here's what it says about John
1:1 from the beginning the word of God
was there the word stood by the side of
God and the Word was fully
God y'all put fully in the chat for me
please does the clear word demot Jesus
from being God like the New World
Translation does
no it does
not fact check number six is false not
only is fact check number six false look
at uh uh 1 Timothy chapter 3:16 in the
clear word there's no question that the
mystery of our religion is great God
manifest In the Flesh confirmed by the
Holy Spirit worshiped By Angels
proclaimed among the Nations believed on
in the world and taken bodily to Heaven
no you guys the clear word does not
demote Jesus neither do Seventh Day
Adventist which brings us back to fact
check number three and four do Adventist
believe that Jesus was promoted to deity
and that Jesus and Lucifer were once
equals oh man that sounds like the
Mormons to me not Adventist LDS oh s d
oh that's not the same
maybe maybe you got that mixed
up maybe you got that mixed up
from Everlasting this is Ellen White the
review and Herald April 5th 1906 from
Everlasting the while God's word speaks
of the humanity of Christ when he was
upon upon the Earth it also speaks
decidedly regarding his pre-existence
the word existed as a Divine being even
as the Eternal Son of God in Union and
Oneness with his father from Everlasting
he was the mediator of the
Covenant the one in whom all nations of
the Earth both Jews and Gentiles if they
accepted him were to be blessed the word
was with God and the Word was God before
men or Angels were
created the word was with God and was
God not became God was God how is it
possible to believe that God was ex
Jesus was exalted to deity but also the
Adventist reject the deity of Christ how
does that even make sense no beloved
Jesus was not at one time Lucifer's
equal no beloved Jesus was not promoted
to deity you are
misreading the writings of Ellen
White do SD believe like jws regarding
Michael let's break it down how y'all
doing so
far are we okay how are we doing so far
put a one in the chat if we're doing
good so far I know we got a bunch of
people on here some of you are are are
pro- Adventists and some of you are
anti- Adventist you came on here you
know wanting to see and just figure out
okay what is it an ADV Adventist believe
and I believe that you're here because
you're genuinely wanting to understand
truth and that's okay that's that's good
you know you may even be slanted one way
or another and you're like I just want
to know the truth so so I hope beloved
that as you're listening to this you may
say well I'll never be an Adventist but
one thing I know is that what was said
about them was a lie right you even have
non-adventist uh defending Adventist
online they're making videos to be like
absolutely they might be you know you
may not agree with them here here and
here but they're not a cult absolutely
and they broke it down actually very
beautifully yes they did so now check
this out y'all I'm GNA see how fast I
can get through this okay a and the ones
coming up hopefully will be will be a
little bit quicker but let's go back to
the
screen
so here is a
picture of Eric Mason's Facebook
page this picture that Eric Mason
took of himself holding a book is called
the deity of Jesus Christ in the olden
New Testament you can see the date there
June 25th and to me that looks like
Elsie
I'm sorry that looks like Eric Mason
he's holding a book called The deity of
Jesus
Christ and when I saw that book I said
hm let me go purchase that book because
he everybody was like oh Pastor Mason
I'm going to purchase that book I'm
going to purchase that book so I
purchased the book too and uh in the
book very interesting it's talking about
the deity of Christ in the Old Testament
and I just want you to I'm going to read
these just straight through okay so bear
with me as I read we're getting through
our slides okay so so and there's many
people to say take your time Pastor
don't feel so so rushed the the book
mentions the angel of the Lord 118
times this book that Eric Mason is
promoting okay the angel of the Lord is
mentioned 118 times let me read to you
some of these disagreements
okay I'm I'm sorry disagreement some of
these
statements
in this book and listen if people are
are uh I hope no one is
like anyway let let's let's be
respectable in the comments okay I'm not
really looking at the comments but let's
just make sure that that there's respect
going on uh in the comments okay you
focus on that and I'll match comments
okay in theological circles this is
known as a theophany where in the Old
Testament times God Appears in the form
of man in verse 14 Hagar names the well
bear laahi Roy which means The Well of
him who lives and sees me God is not the
only one who has life in himself I'm
sorry God is the only one who has life
in himself self-existent and is
omnipresent able to see us no matter
where where we are as Hagar was in the
wilderness these attributes are ascribed
to the angel of the Lord who is called
God which can be none other than Jesus
Christ please note that in this book the
angel of the the the author says that
the angel of the Lord is Jesus Christ
again he says angel means messenger this
messenger from God who spoke to Abraham
and declared to Abraham the ways of God
and is declared God can be none other
than God's word here's another quote
Jesus Christ the angel of the messenger
or the angel or messenger is called
Jehovah God once again we see the deity
of the angel of God who can be none
other than Jesus Christ in his
pre-incarnate mystery we see the
omniscience of Jehovah God he whose name
is I am the angel of the Lord namely the
Lord Jesus Christ listen to me y'all
this book that that that Eric Mason has
in his hand literally is saying over and
over again that there is an angel in the
Bible who is not actually an angel as as
in a created being but is Jesus himself
God himself let's keep reading the angel
of the Lord and the Lord are used
interchangeably proving there is no
difference as the angel of the Lord is
the Lord Jesus Christ the one who
reveals the father in the old as well as
the New Testament again the angel of the
Lord is the messenger the word or the
one who declares him to the people who
is Jesus Christ again the angel of God
is a pre-incarnate pre-incarnate
manifestation of the Lord Jesus Christ
who's going forth have been from from of
all
listen to this y'all the Lord God
commanded Israel to keep his sabbaths
since the sabbaths belong to God he is
the lord of the Sabbath Jesus Christ is
the lord of the Sabbath proving he is
the lord god
wow
wow this is absolutely amazing
Jesus is the lord of the Sabbath and
that makes him
God which also connects him with the
angel of the Lord very interesting how
about this the angel of the Lord is the
Lord Jesus Christ equal to the father in
power and Glory which makes him very God
and ve very God of very God the Lord
brought Israel out of the land of Egypt
the angel of the Lord brought Israel out
of the land of Egypt therefore the angel
of the Lord is the Lord God who can be
none other than Jesus Christ since Jesus
Christ is God it was his voice which
Israel heard out of the midst of the
fire on Mount Si the Sabbath is called
the Sabbath of the Lord thy God I'm
sorry we just read that one uh um oh no
let me read it Jesus Christ as the lord
of the Sabbath is the owner of the
Sabbath the day belongs to him therefore
he is The Giver of the Sabbath wow so
Jesus is The Giver of the Sabbath I
thought that wasn't Jesus's commandment
right I thought Jesus's commandment are
different from the Old Testament
commandment M how about this the angel
of the Lord has a name of God which is
which in Christ's name which is Christ's
name proving Jesus Christ is God how
about this the word of God in Hebrew
plural denotes more than one person in
the godhead this God who exists in more
than one person brought Israel out of
Egypt spoke to Israel out of the fire on
M SI and gave them the Ten Commandments
and the Lord whom you seek shall
suddenly come to his Temple even the
messenger of the Covenant the Temple of
the Lord is in the Lord the temple temp
of the Lord is the Temple of the Lord is
his Temple the Temple of the Old
Testament was God's house it belonged to
God he here it says the temple Belongs
to the Lord Jesus Christ of whom Jes
John was the Forerunner and it goes on I
just want to point out here that if
Jesus gave the Ten Commandments then the
Ten Commandments belong to Jesus wow now
now that we've done that and set the
foundation
that Orthodox Christians
right believe that an angel is actually
Jesus yes are you calling these people
cultish because they hold that belief
right you're not they're not they are
not so because we say that that Angel's
name is Michael that that angel has a
name and his name is Michael now we're a
cult all right so so let's just go back
and go back to the screen here's Matthew
Henry who's a
presbyterian his commentary says this
about the angel of the Lord he stood
before the angel of the Lord is before
Christ the lord of the angels to whom
even the high priest themselves of
Aaron's order were accountable here is
John Gil who was a
Baptist speaking about Zechariah
3 he says this the same with the angel
of the Lord in Zechariah 3:1 having
heard the charge brought by him against
Joshua here called Jehovah being the Son
of God and properly God goes on to say
not a created angel but the angel of
God's presence and Covenant the the
Eternal Word and Son of God okay now
Baker's event by the way let me say this
anybody who wants my slides you get them
all you got to do make sure you
subscribe yes subscribe to power of the
Lamb tell me you want the slides yeah
Friend or Foe tell me you want my slides
and I will give them to you you don't
have to go research for yourself I will
give you this
okay so let me go back here's Baker's
Evangelical dictionary of biblical
theology a under Angel of the Lord
here's what it says a supernatural being
who Bears a message on behalf of God in
many passages in the Old Testament the
angel of the Lord is identified With God
all right now watch this y'all I'm G to
skip and I'm going to go right to John
Calvin here's what John Calvin the
founder of the Presbyterian movement of
which LC belongs I was just going to say
I think he's a minister of the Pres
of which LC belongs if I'm not mistaken
listen to what John Calvin said about
Michael Michael May mean an angel but I
embrace the opinion of those who refer
to this person of Christ because it
suits the object best to represent him
as standing forward for the defense of
his elect people the angel calls Michael
the mighty Prince as if he said said
Michael should be the guardian and
protector of the elect people this is
John
Calvin you all he's not an Adventist
here is John Gil pastors have these
commentaries all up in their
libraries speaking about Michael
standing up the Archangel who has all
the angels of heaven under him and at
his command the Son of God our Lord
Jesus Christ who is as God as the name
signifies the name Michael means one who
is as God and equal in nature power and
glory to his Divine father here's
Matthew Henry Michael signifies who is
like God and his name with the title of
great savior points out the divine
Savior Christ stood for the children of
our people in their stad as a sacrifice
bore the curse for them for them to BU
it here's the Geneva Study Bible the
Protestant Bible the Protestant Bible
during the Dark Ages the angel here
notes two things first first that the
church will be in great Affliction and
trouble at Christ's coming and next that
God will send his Angel to deliver it
whom here he calls Michael meaning
Christ you guys let me say this none of
these people believed that Jesus was a
created being right they believed as
Preston was pointing out right that
Michael is simply another name for
Christ Christ is not a created angel no
he is God yes are you going to call John
Calvin a a cultist right how about this
guy right here Charles Spurgeon who in a
sermon in
1866 said this you remember how our Lord
who is the true Michael the only great
Archangel said at the beginning of the
preaching of the Gospel I beheld Satan
as Lightning falling from Heaven okay
y'all is Charles Spurgeon has did he
lose his
mind did he lose is he crazy no he was
was he reading Ellen White no he was not
were any of these guys reading Ellen
White to get this teaching which
apparently only Adventists believe yeah
see here's a problem you guys here's the
problem a lot of people will take
advantage of the fact that y'all are not
GNA study so they think they can just
throw stuff out and have the you know oh
they're a cult okay I don't want to have
I don't want to hear anything else they
have to say and that is very powerful it
works the easiest and laziest
way well to get somebody to just not
just say oh yeah they're a
cult I'm coming Verona to sdas have
their own Bible I haven't forgotten that
that's part of our fat
check so let's go back and let's let's
keep watching y'all Adam Clark's
commentary let it be observed that the
word Archangel is never found in the
plural number in the sacred writings
there can be properly only one Archangel
one Chief or head of the Angelic host
Michael is this Archangel and the head
of all Angelic orders hence by this
personage in the apocalypse many
understand the Lord
Jesus not
everybody but many understand the Lord
Jesus you guys all I am saying is it is
a it is it is very erroneous to act like
oh only Adventists have ever believed
this and therefore they are a cult the
the the average person is not going to
take the time to be like okay well let
me go check out what he said no when you
when you play on your Authority I was
the best in school I'm a scholar I was
this I was that I know it in and out and
then small fish was no smallfish and so
now I don't have to give receipts for
the stuff I say I can just say it and
people will just believe it you guys
this is why the Bible says broad is the
road that leads to destruction and
narrow is the way that leads to eternal
life why because group
think the majority must always be right
yeah the majority doesn't make you right
the majority doesn't make you wrong mhm
but when when it comes to the Bible
beloved you can't just sit back and just
be like oh well he must know what he's
talking about so right let me uh let me
just go ahead and believe him let me
just go ahead and believe her you can't
do that because people will take
advantage of your
ignorance let me go back now go ahead
John Gil John gil on Jude 19 so Michael
in Jude 19 with which compare revelation
127 and who perhaps is none other than
Christ himself I think I read that one
already let me go to the fundamental
beliefs of the Adventist Church
regarding Jesus here is our fundamental
belief regarding Jesus God the Eternal
son became incarnate in Jesus Christ
through him all things were created the
character of God is revealed the
salvation of humanity is accomplished
and the world is judged forever truly
God he became also truly human Jesus the
Christ I'm not going to read anymore I
just need y'all to see beloved that
people will take advantage of your
ignorance don't let them do that you I'm
not telling you become an Adventist I'm
just saying don't let people lie to you
and don't let people say oh I'm a
scholar so you could trust me you don't
have to do your own research oh it's all
over the place don't do that always ask
for the receipts always and study for
yourself to connect do dot for yourself
how many people rejected Jesus because
they listen to the Pharisees and
Sadducees say man that guy is off don't
listen to him don't trust anyone trust
God and do your own study don't trust me
yeah I was going to say that don't trust
any of these other men you trust God you
trust the Bible because man is fallible
yes so you've got to know for yourself
is this truth or is this error I'm not
just going to blindly listen to someone
and be like Oh well man
they no no guys you don't do that and
let me say it again
y'all I'm reading a whole lot of stuff
that's not Bible verses I know that but
the reason why is because what was
presented in this response it wasn't
Bible it was verses so what am I what am
I to respond to mhm three Bible
verses no there was way more error
presented as you can see let's go back
to the screen I'm trying to move through
this rapidly y'all so please bear with
me here is Ellen White on Jesus Christ
is the pre-existent self-existent Son of
God in speaking of his pre-existence
Christ carries the Mind back through
dateless ages he assures us that there
was never a time when he was not in
close fellowship with the Eternal God
again she says this not one of the
Angels could have become sh for the
human race for their life is gods they
could not surrender it the angels all
wear the Yoke of obedience they are the
appointed messengers of him who is the
commander of all heaven but Christ is
equal with God infinite and omnipotent
he could pay the ransom for man's
Freedom he is the Eternal self-existing
son upon whom no yoke had come when God
asked whom shall I send he could reply
here I am send me he could pledge
himself to be man shity for he could say
that which the highest Angel could not
say I have power over my own life power
to lay it down and power to take it up
again and then in the Desire of Ages she
says this in
Christ is
Life
original unborrowed
UND derived how much pler let's come
back to the screen how much pler
can this be made how
mucher you guys we still have I don't
know I think 10 more points of to of
factchecking but let me say this because
I don't I don't think we're we're gonna
I don't know what's going to happen we
might go through it all I don't know
what's G I'm just in the moment right
now but let me say this if I've gone
through seven fact checks so
far and they have all been absolutely
incorrect absolutely
error do we need to go through those
other points if it if it just stop there
you got to ask yourself how can I trust
anything else they have to say about the
Bible they didn't say much about the
Bible what they said was apparently
history of the Adventist Church but if
if if this is
wrong if this is absolute error I'm not
trying to poison the well here trust me
I'm not I could have just said look at
this one error so don't listen to
anything anything else they have to say
but what I'm saying is look at how many
I'm showing you that the water is
actually poisoned I'm not just saying oh
the water's poisoned don't worry about
it I'm showing you that the water is
actually poisoned and I'm showing you
every drop of poison here's a drop
here's a drop here's a drop here's a
drop here's a drop here's a drop here
it's all over mhm it's all over some
wells are actually
poisoned okay let's go back to the
screen are you okay yeah you good I'm
good let's go back to the screen you
know I speak up if I'm not yeah I'm just
going to go till my wife tells me you
need to stop the Lord Elie yeah here's
what Elsie says listen to this listen to
this statement ready let's go Ellen
White has a lot of statements in which
she say for example the Lord Jesus
Christ is not the Lord God Almighty and
this is sacran teaching for the
Adventist Ellen White has a lot of
statements in which she say for example
the Lord Jesus Christ is not the Lord
God Almighty and this is sacran teaching
for the
Adventist however you have to understand
the way their mind work in terms of
cognitive dissonance and the doctrine
and theology whatever it is is very
contradictory based on l writings so you
you can always find quotes and
statements and teachings from their
prophet's writings that
support
Ellen Ellen White has a lot of
statements in which he say for example
the Lord Jesus Christ is not the Lord
God Almighty and this is sacran teaching
forth the
Adventist however you have to understand
the way their mind
work Ellen White has a lot of statements
in which she say for example the Lord
Jesus Christ is not the Lord God
Almighty and this is sacran teaching for
the
Adventist however you have to understand
the way their mind work in terms of
cognitive dissonance and the doctrine
and theology whatever it is is very
contradictory based on Ellen White's
writing so you you can always find
quotes and statements and teachings from
their prophet's writings that support
any position that you want to
hold okay so let me tell you what's
happening here let me tell you what's
happening here um so Skeptics of the
Bible have this same position of the
Bible
the Bible contradicts itself so you can
find any position in the Bible and go
with that that's a very weak argument
but what the argument is designed to do
is it's designed to nullify again
anything
anything that is said because now if I
show you oh no Ellen White believes that
Jesus is a Divine being you're going to
be like oh yeah but you know her
writings contradict itself we can we
Skeptics say the same thing about the
Bible James says you're saved by faith
and
works elsewhere it says you're only
saved by faith through
Grace that's what Skeptics will do and
it's funny how the Christian will
typically go bend over backward to try
to show the harmony between two
apparently contradicting verses in the
Bible but y'all not yall not going to
give that
same
courtesy to something else but you'll
demand it when the skeptic comes and
says oh look at where the Bible says
here this and then the Bible says here
that the Bible clearly contradicts
itself yeah did Ellen White say the Lord
Jesus Christ was not the Lord God
Almighty let's see let's go to the
screen let's go to the screen here's a
statement that he's quoting there is no
one who can explain The Mystery of the
Incarnation of Christ yet we know that
he came to this earth and lived as a man
among
men the man wait wait wait the Lord
Jesus Christ no no no no no no no no the
man Jesus Christ or Christ Jesus was not
the Lord God Almighty yet Christ and the
father are one the deity did not sink
under the agonizing torture of the C of
calvary yet it is nonetheless true that
that God so loved the world that he gave
his only begotten son that whosoever
believeth in him should not perish but
have everlasting life you guys listen
what is Ellen White saying here she is
simply saying that when God the
almighty Lord became
Jesus he could bleed
yeah he didn't bring with him his
Almighty power you could cut him mhm he
could be bruised MH he got hungry mhm he
got tired he got
tired context is key you cannot just
take a text misquoted and then be like
yep and therefore she doesn't believe
that Jesus is God
what now listen let me let me make an
apology here um you guys this thing has
been brewing in my soul since the first
day I was minding my business business
and somebody sent me the very first
video Pastor have you seen this it's
been brewing in my soul so
listen if if I have come across as
passionate and if I've said anything
that was offensive in any way please
accept my apology right I'm not trying
to be offensive and I'm not trying to be
crude in any way and listen someone like
some of you were like Pastor you know
don't defend this is not about defending
myself right there are many people who
have questions many people who are
genuinely confused many young Adventists
that were like wait do we believe that
and and many non Adventists like wait I
know Adventist and they're pretty good
people do y'all believe that
right God calls us to stand for
truth so so let me not divert on this
too long all I'm simply saying
is if you see me being very passionate
please just understand right this is not
per personal for me but it is personal
for me because truth is personal for me
right every one of those guys Mason is a
soul that that that that wants to be
saved I believe Elsie's a soul that
wants to be saved we're all looking and
seeking and want wanting to make sure
that we are in the truth and following
the truth and sometimes your own
convictions can lead you to fight
against something that you don't even re
realize you're fighting against so Paul
why are you kicking against the PRS mhmm
so so
again I'm just
asking grant me
that that you know I'm
human and listen y'all y'all know my
testimony from being out in the world
was somebody came from my crew it was
like no we're not doing that and y'all
are coming from my
crew right and and and the thing is you
know it's not me that anyone of anyone
of of of my crew my ex-men my Christian
brothers and sisters any one of them
could do what I'm doing tonight right
any one of them some of you like hey
Pastor y y'all can see I have so much to
say right now I was like if we bring
somebody else on they will have the same
amount of stuff to and we'll just never
get anything done that's why he brought
me and that's why I was just like tante
you come on and just monitor me and but
we're going to follow up on this and and
and we're going to have other people on
like I we still there there's going to
be a group of us that come together you
know like somebody said there's a series
Brewing I do believe there's a series
Brewing it's going to happen it's going
to happen and I like to tell people that
and just since we're on your your this
passion side taking just a little break
from all of that um I like a little
break a little break it's not long it's
a little break it's a little break um
just that this is the study of God's
word and connecting the dots and proving
the truth in God's word this is his
basketball this is his football this is
his you fill in the blank of people when
they get very passionate about you know
most men and and women can you know are
heavily into those to those sporting
events or those activities and they get
very passionate about it this is Pastor
Myers's basketball and football and I
can I can yeah and you're see and you're
seeing some very pent up cuz it's been
pent up y'all I've been waiting for the
opportunity and like too much I wish
that we were able to do this on the
Perry's podcast with Perry cuz I think
PR is the kind of guy that we could have
sat down and been like all right and he
could have just been like so all right
they said this but what do you you know
without that debating spirit because
often debates don't get anywhere no is
you know someone said your side is
always going to think you win the other
side is always going to think they but
to just sit down with Preston and been
like hey so actually here's what we
believe no we don't believe that I think
PR would have been like ah okay I didn't
know that man I was anyway let's go to
fact check number six y'all